

[Arya Danih Lesmana]

Bekasi, Jawa Barat, 17139 | +62 812 8545 9751 | aryadanihlesmana@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Arya Danih Lesmana | **Instagram** : @araydl_ | Portofolio : https://araraya.github.io/portofolio2/

About Me

I'm a self-taught programmer that passionate about Mobile and Web Development. Currently, I'am focusing in more Mobile Development using Cross-Platform technology. I have a passion for solving a problem and building great UI that can make user comfortable for using then application. One way or approach in solving problems is by building technology or software to be a solution to a problem. Although I only have a little experience. But I am optimistic that I can provide the best solution or software to solve the problems you are facing.

Ability and Skills

- ArcGIS Product
- QGIS
- Google Earth Engine
- ENVI
- WebGIS
- Global Mapper
- PCI Geomatica
- Drone Mapping
- Python
- Avenza Maps

- Microsoft Office
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Priemer Pro
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- React
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- Flutter

Education

• State University of Jakarta (2017- January 2022) Geography

• Vocational High School Bina Siswa Utama Bekasi (2014-2016)

Computer and Network Engineering

Work Experience

1. Surveyor

Freelance

Badan Pusat Statistik Kota Bekasi (February 2022 – March 2022)

- Updating SLS boundaries in Bekasi City.
- Gathering land cover sample for accuracy assesmen.

2. GIS Operator

Fulltime

PT. ICTIndo Mita Solusi (October 2021 – January 2022)

• Make a large spatial dataset to building BIG Data, that can provide a solution to business insight or problem of company client.

3. GIS Engineer

Bappedalitbang Kabupaten Bogor (August – September 2021)

 Make a GIS Dashboard that visualize COVID-19 Death in Bogor Regency to help local government handling covid rising death rate.

4. Data Analyst

Internship

MAPID (June - August 2021)

 Making a project that solve problem using location or geospatial data especially for bussiness decision.

5. Research Assistant

Freelance

Universitas Negeri Jakarta (June – July 2021)

• Support researcher to perform data gathering and analysis of research.

6. GIS Intern Team Lead

Internship

Esri Indonesia (Maret – Juli 2021)

- Coordinating the team to achieve goals, and combining solutions to use in some industry sector
- Make a project to solve a problem using ArcGIS Platform

7. GIS Analyst

Freelance

Kementrian Pertanian Republik Indonesia (April – Juni 2021)

Compile and analyze OPLAH data (Optimization of Swamp and Rice Fields)

Achievements and Awards

1. 2nd Winner in Creative Video Competition "Utilization of Remote Sensing in the Field of Disaster Mitigation"

Padang State University (2020)

2. Speakers of the 2020 National Geomatics Seminar

Geospatial Information Agency (2020)

3. ArcNesia Community Challenge Category of Most Likes

ESRI Indonesia (2020)

Scientific Publications

1. Analisis Perubahan Garis Pantai Menggunakan Teknik Penginderaan Jauh di Pulau Pramuka, Kepulauan Seribu

Seminar Nasional Geomatika 2020

Geospatial Information Agency (2021)

Volunteer Experience

1. Mapper

October 2020

Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team

• Mapping buildings, roads and parks around Bandung, West Bandung and TasikmalayaDistricts to increase Disaster Capacity.

2. Mapper

April 2020

Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team

• Mapping and completing data on health facilities throughout Indonesia to respond to COVID-19. Successfully ranked 1st in the leaderboard.

Organizational Experience

1. Club K, English Club of Faculty of Social Science, UNJ (2017-2019)

Learning Division Staff

• Plan, coordinate, lead, and supervise monthly English class discussions. Successfully helda 2019 Social Speech Contest.

2. Student Executive Board Geography Education Study Program UNJ (2019)

KPSDM Staff

- Cadre members of BEMP Geography.
- Monitor and support all members of BEMP Geography.
- Planning, coordinating, arranging leadership training events.

3. Praktik Kuliah Lapangan Sosial, Ekonomi dan Pemetaan Desa Gitgit, Kab. Buleleng, Bali (2019) Chief Executive

• Designing events and coordinating with all elements of the committee, supervisors and village officials. Managed to run the event smoothly until it was finished, and produced aSocial, Economic and Mapping Study Report of Gitgit Village, Kab. Buleleng, Bali.

4. Praktik Kuliah Lapangan Sosial, Ekonomi dan Pemetaan Desa Gitgit, Kab. Buleleng, Bali (2019)

Leader of the Digital Mapping Group

- Designing, and collecting spatial data in Gitgit Village, Kab. Buleleng, Bali.
- Distribute tasks with group members and village authorities for map making
- Successfully made a map of the Gitgit Village, Kab. Buleleng, Bali

5. Student Executive Board of the Faculty of Social Sciences, UNJ (2020)

Kominfo Department Staff

• Create written content on the website and publish monthly magazines. Successfullycreated a website, wrote 9 articles and published 8 digital magazines.

6. Praktik Kuliah Lapangan Terpadu Virtual, Desa Plosoharjo, Kec. Toroh, Kab. Grobogan(2020)

Leader of the Mapping Group

- Designing analytical studies, collecting spatial data, and compiling the study map of Plosoharjo Village.
- Distribute tasks with group members and coordinate with village authorities.
- Successfully made a basic map, namely the map of administration, land ownership, rainfall, soil type, slope, lineament density, river density, lithology, land use, and watershed.
- Successfully made an Analysis Map, namely a Groundwater Potential Map and a Red Onion Land Suitability Map.
- Successfully created the Plosoharjo Village WebGIS.

Training and Seminars

1. ESRI

The Location Advantage (3 June 2021)

2. 7th Asia-Pasific Conference on Synthetic Aperture Radar 2021

Online Tutorial Series 6 on Synthetic Aperture Radar (3 June 2021)

3. 7th Asia-Pasific Conference on Synthetic Aperture Radar 2021

Online Tutorial Series on Synthetic Aperture Radar (11 March 2021)

4. DQLAB

Fundamental SQL Using INNER JOIN and UNION (28 January 2021)

5. DQLAB

Fundamental SQL Using FUNCTION and GROUP BY (28 January 2021)

6. DQLAB

Fundamental SQL Using SELECT Statement (28 January 2021)

7. DQLAB

Exploratory Data Analysis with Python for Beginner (28 January 2021)

8. DQLAB

Python for Data Professional Beginner - Part 3 (28 January 2021)

9. DQLAB

Python for Data Professional Beginner - Part 2 (27 January 2021)

10. DQLAB

Python for Data Professional Beginner - Part 1 (7 January 2021)

11. DQLAB

Python Fundamental for Data Science (4 January 2021)

12. DQLAB

Introduction to Data Science with Python (4 January 2021)

13. Geosoftware Community

Machine Learning in Python and Its Application Examples (18 – 19 December 2020)

14. ESRI

Spatial Data Science (29 October – 16 December 2020)

15. Geosoftware Community

Machine Learning with R for Landslide Prediction (11 – 12 December 2020)

16. Geosoftware Community

Komputasi Awan di Bidang Penginderaan Jauh Gunung Api dengan Google Earth Engine (GEE)(2 -6 December 2020)

17. REGISTER (Remote Sensing and Geographic Information System Technology Research) UNDIP Coastal Environment In The Face of Climate Change (15 November 2020)

18. REGISTER (Remote Sensing and Geographic Information System Technology Research) UNDIPThe Impact of Climate Change in Coastal Environment (13 - 14 November 2020)

19. Geospatial Information Agency

2020 National Geomatics Seminar (15 - 16 October 2020)

20. Geosoftware Community

Python Basics and Its Applications in Geosciences and Geospatial (28 August - 11 October 2020)

21. MAPIN

SAR FOR GEOLOGY AND DISASTER APPLICATION (21 September 2020)

22. LAPAN

Remote Sensing for Forest Fires (18 September 2020)

23. LAPAN

Remote Sensing for Mangroves (11 September 2020)

24. Geosoftware Community

ArcGIS Pro dan ArcGIS Online (10 - 22 August 2020)

25. Geosoftware Community

Basic Geospatial Information System Using QGIS (11 July - 2 August 2020)

26. SinauGIS

WebGIS Online Training with Spreadsheet Leaflet for COVID-19 Data Visualization (4 May - 6 July 2020)

27. JRS-GIS Center

Basic, Advanced, and Web Based GIS Training WebGIS (17 - 18 July 2020)

28. Mapperindo

Introduction and Basic Processing of LiDAR Data for Urban and Regional Planning Studies (3 July 2020)

29. Geosoftware Community

Remote Sensing and GIS Applications for Various Jobs in the Field of Geoscience (2 -27 June 2020)

30. Geospatial Information Agency

Geospatial Information Competency Certification: Can it Boost Human Resources Quality and GI Industry Performance? (19 June 2020)

31. Geotronix

Lebih Dalam Lagi Tentang Survei Multibeam: Backscatter (18 Juni 2020)

32. Geospatial Information Agency

InaTEWS: Disaster Preparedness (12 June 2020)

33. Geospatial Information Agency

Geospatial Information of Raw Paddy Land (9 June 2020)

34. Mapperindo

Utilization of Remote Sensing, Identification of Land Cover Using Guided and Unsupervised Classification Methods (6 June 2020)

35. Geospatial Information Agency

One Map Policy and Perpres on Jabodetabek Spatial Planning (5 June 2020)

36. Geographical Information Science Study Program, FKIP, Indonesian Education

University Scientific and technological developments and prospects for the world of work in the field of geospatial information (5 June 2020)

37. Geosoftware Community & Esri Indonesia

GIS Application in Handling COVID-19 (2 - 4 June 2020)

38. Esa Unggul University

Mapping Personnel, Universities and Opportunities in the World of Work (1 June 2020)

39. Esri

Cartography (25 April - 2 Juni 2020)

40. Waindo SpeccTera

GIS Enterprise / Operation Dashboard, CSRT, Airbone, LiDAR and their Utilization Applications (19 May 2020)

41. University of Indonesia & Esri Indonesia

Utilization of WebGIS for Tectonic Earthquake Disaster Mitigation (30 November 2019)

42. The Southeast Asian Regional Centre for Tropical Biology

Training of Trainers (ToT) on Application Acoustic Technology for Underwater Object StudiesMarine Biota Inventory and Conservation (5 - 9 Agustus 2019)

43. The Southeast Asian Regional Centre for Tropical Biology
Drone Training (UAV) for Rapid Disaster Mapping (20 July 2019)